# Leonardo Faria

15+ years of experience in design, architecture, development, and delivery of SaaS products and websites

Seeking engineering roles in a product-driven organization. With my work, I bring creative and customer-focused solutions with attention to detail and a pragmatic approach. Previously in a manager path, I have experience delivering work that matters for customers and growing products and people

**Interests:** Front-end, technical leadership, architecture, mentorship, Continuous Integration, Design System, Developer Experience

# Experience

### Lattice

#### San Francisco / Remote

### **Staff Software Engineer**

Apr 2022 — Present

- Led projects in a new 0 to 1 company initiative with TypeScript and React
- Improved testing by creating documentation, guidelines and building a CI tool to track test coverage across different teams
- Improved developer experience tools and documentation
- Advocated for accessibility by leveraging automated tests

#### Thinkific

Vancouver

#### **Technical Architect - Front-end**

Sep 2020 — Mar 2022

- Improved Front-end performance by: introducing Lighthouse testing in CI; refactoring the product to support webp and working on different projects to improve page load and user experience
- Worked closely with teams to demonstrate the feasibility of technical solutions in upcoming projects, bridging product and engineering
- Partnered with the Chief Architect defining technical vision and technical strategy
- Supported the Design System solution (used by different React and Ruby on Rails applications), especially in CI and accessibility tasks

#### **Engineering Team Lead**

Oct 2017 — Sep 2020

- Led a team of up to 7 back-end/front-end engineers working on projects for different customer personas (course creators/students)
- Provided mentorship, collected and delivered feedback; set goals for engineer reports and conducted performance reviews
- Owned projects end-to-end, including the redesign of the product, React adoption, and the creation of the Thinkific Design System (2018 — present)
- Grew the team by proactively sourcing ICs. Successfully recruited 4 engineers by partnering with the HR department and working on creative ways to find talent
- Led different initiatives in R&D (All-hands, onboarding of new members, hackathons) while the company scaled from 50 to 300 employees

### **Senior Software Engineer**

Nov 2016 — Oct 2017

Worked on different customer-facing projects mostly focusing on front-end and using Ruby on Rails and Ember.js

# **Dynamic Leap Technology**

# Feb 2016 — Nov 2016

Vancouver

Full Stack Developer (contract work)

- Developed websites using WordPress for Dynamic Leap and its clients
- Built MVPs for clients using Ember.js and Ruby on Rails APIs.

604media Vancouver

### Full Stack Developer (contract work)

Oct 2015 - Jan 2016

- Maintained Intranet applications (PHP/Laravel) and WordPress websites for agency clients
- Maintained iOS/Android apps built with Phonegap

### Ministry of Social Security

Brasilia, Brazil

### **Full Stack Developer**

Sep 2011 — Aug 2015

- Developed and maintained new and legacy Intranet applications used by thousands of civil servants in Brazil between 2011 - 2018
- Developed the Ministry of Social Security website using WordPress (still in use by millions of citizens)
- Created one of the first iOS and Android apps in the public sector using Cordova

Freelance Brazil

### **Full Stack Developer**

2006 - 2015

- Built custom-made Ruby on Rails applications for B2B (fast fashion companies)
- Created WordPress websites for 10+ clients partnering with a designer and using PHP & jQuery
- Built "Writing for IELTS and TOEFL" (app for iOS/Android) using Ionic

# **Education**

### Langara College

Vancouver

Web and Mobile App Development / Post-Degree Diploma

2015 - 2016

### **Pitagoras University**

Brazil

Bachelor of Information Systems

2006 - 2011

# Other

## **Ladies Learning Code**

Vancouver

Instructed workshops including HTML & CSS for Beginners and WordPress for Beginners as a volunteer

2017 - 2019

Speaker

Vancouver

Spoke in different meetups and conferences. Slides in

2015 - 2019

https://leonardofaria.net/talks